Guide to the Tokichi Okazaki Papers 1915-1930
Washington State University Libraries: Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
Tokichi Okazaki Papers
1915-1930
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Terrell Library Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 107
Okazaki, Tokichi
1 container. .5 linear feet of shelf space. 80 items.
Letters, in Japanese, from relatives in Japan, principally describing everyday happenings. Also, some miscellaneous receipts and papers from Japanese organizations and businesses in the Northwest.
Little is known about Tokichi Okazaki. Judging from the papers, he was a resident in Seattle and Pasco, Washington between 1900 and 1930. He appears to have been an employee of the Northern Pacific Railroad.
The papers of Tokichi Okazaki principally consist of his incoming correspondence, in Japanese. The content of the letters deal with everyday happenings in Japan. Names of addressers are Tokujiro Okazaki, Mitsu Okazaki, Toshiko Okazaki and others. The relationships between them are hard to identify, except in the case of Toshiki, a daughter of Tokichi Okazaki. The others can be assumed to be brothers or other close relatives of Tokishi Okazaki. There are also a few miscellaneous papers concerning Japanese associations in the U. S. such as Japanese Association of Northern America, Japanese Buddhist Association, Oregon, and Japanese Baptist Church, Seattle.
The papers have been arranged in two series with the first series, correspondence, in a chronological sequence, and the miscellaneous papers separated into a second series.
This collection is open for research use.
The Tokichi Okazaki papers were found in an old laundry in Pasco, Washington in 1967.
The Tokichi Okazaki papers were donated to the Washington State University Library by David Griffith in 1977.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Okazaki, Tokichi --Archives; Griffith, David. waps
Japanese -- Washington (State)--Correspondence; Japan--Social conditions--1912-1945--Sources
Japanese Americans; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - To Tokichi Okazaki
    - 1915, 1 item. (Folder 1)
    - February-June, 1916, 10 items. (Folder 2)
    - July-December, 1916, 15 items. (Folder 3)
    - 1917, 7 items. (Folder 4)
    - 1918, 2 items. (Folder 5)
    - 1919, 1 item. (Folder 6)
    - 1920, 1 item. (Folder 7)
    - 1925, 5 items. (Folder 8)
    - 1926, 3 items. (Folder 9)
    - 1927, 1 item. (Folder 10)
    - 1928, 3 items. (Folder 11)
    - 1929, 3 items. (Folder 12)
    - 1930, 4 items. (Folder 13)
    - undated, 10 items. (Folder 14)
  - To T. Hirao and M. Nishimira
    - T. Hirao, undated; 1 item. (Folder 15)
    - M. Nishimira, December 8, 1930; 1 item. (Folder 16)
- Series 2: Miscellaneous
  - Japanese Associations in the U.S., 3 items. (Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 26 items. (Folder 18)
  - Medicine Advertisement, 1 item. (Folder 19)